Guide to the Jean Webster Papers, 1876–1982 (bulk 1900-1916)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Jean Webster Papers
1876-1982
1900-1916
Webster, Jean, 1876-1916
13.0 cubic feet (52 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
The Jean Webster Papers at the Vassar College Libraries Department of Special Collections are part of the McKinney Family Papers, a collection of papers from the Clemens, Moffett, Webster, and McKinney families. They were donated to Vassar College in 1977, along with the endowment of a chair in American Literature, in honor of Jean Webster. The donors are Jean McKinney Connor, daughter of Jean Webster and Glenn Ford McKinney, and her husband Ralph Connor, a former trustee of Vassar.
Biographical Note
Jean Webster, christened Alice Jane Chandler Webster, was born in Fredonia, NY on July 24, 1876. Her mother, Annie Moffett Webster, was a niece of Mark Twain. Her father, Charles Luther Webster, was Twain's partner and publisher in the ill-fated Charles L. Webster Publishing Company.
Webster's education included several years at the Fredonia Normal School, graduating in 1894 in china painting, and in 1897 from the college division. From 1894-1896, she attended the Lady Jane Grey boarding school in Binghamton, NY. It was at Lady Jane Grey that she changed her name from Alice to Jean when she discovered that her roommate was also named Alice. In 1897 she entered Vassar College as a member of the class of 1901. As an undergraduate Jean Webster wrote a weekly column of "chatty news" for the Poughkeepsie Sunday Courier and a number of stories for the Vassar Miscellany. It was also at Vassar that she met Adelaide Crapsey, the poet, who remained her close friend until Crapsey's death in 1914.
After graduating from Vassar, Webster earned her living as a free-lance writer and novelist, living in New York City. Her first novel, When Patty Went to College, was published in 1903. It chronicled the trials, tribulations, and adventures of life at a women's college. Altogether Webster wrote eight novels and countless unpublished stories and plays, in a style often described as realistic, refreshing, and witty. Daddy Long-Legs, the story of an orphan whose anonymous benefactor sends her to college, was a best seller and later adapted to the stage by Henry Miller, starring Ruth Chatterton. The play enjoyed a long and successful run in New York, and also toured the Midwest, California, and London. Later film versions starred Mary Pickford and Janet Gaynor, among others.
Jean Webster possessed a love of travel her entire life, beginning with a semester abroad in France, Italy, and England while at Vassar. In 1906/07 she embarked on a world tour with Ethelyn McKinney, her future sister-in-law, and Lena Weinstein, a close friend. Together the women journeyed to Egypt, India, Southeast Asia, China, and Japan.
Webster also had a deep interest in many social reform movements. She was concerned for the plight of orphans and in orphan asylum reform as well as prison reform. In addition, she was a staunch suffragist. One interesting episode in Webster's life was the incident when she was called to jury duty because the authorities had assumed she was a man. Since she was a woman, however, she was not allowed to serve on a jury, much to her chagrin.
For seven years Jean Webster was secretly engaged to Glenn Ford McKinney, a wealthy lawyer and son of the oil magnate John Luke McKinney. Glenn, married to another woman who was plagued by bouts of insanity and weighed down by personal problems himself, couldn't help but submit to Jean's sunny disposition and charm. He finally obtained a divorce in June of 1915, and he and Jean were married among a flurry of activity on September 7, about the same time that "Daddy Long-Legs" was touring and its sequel, Dear Enemy, was published. The McKinneys made their home at Tymor Farm, in Union Vale, Dutchess County, NY, a sanctuary of fields, deer, wild ducks, and pheasants. On the evening of June 10, 1916, the inseparable Ethelyn McKinney and Lena Weinstein accompanied Jean to Sloane Hospital in New York City for the delivery of her baby girl, Jean Webster McKinney. The next morning, June 11, Jean Webster died of complications from childbirth.
For further information, see Alan Simpson's Mark Twain Goes Back To Vassar: An Introduction to the Jean Webster McKinney Family Papers and Jean Webster: Storyteller, by Alan and Mary Simpson with Ralph Connor.
Scope and Content Note
The Jean Webster Papers encompass most of Jean Webster's adult life. They include some correspondence to friends and family, college notebooks, travel journals, as well as later notebooks filled with story ideas, suggestions, and drafts. The collection also includes original manuscripts of unpublished short stories and plays, although none of the final drafts of her novels or the stage adaptation of Daddy Long-Legs remain. Memorabilia and realia include playbills, reviews, photographs, and newspaper clippings chronicling the success of Daddy Long-Legs and other novels and plays; her travels; and family and friends. The researcher should also be aware that only a few of the letters from Jean Webster to Glenn Ford McKinney, and none of the letters from Glenn to Jean survived the years. The letters Jean Webster wrote to Glenn Ford McKinney are located in the Glenn Ford McKinney papers at the Vassar College Libraries Department of Special Collections.
Two addendums to the Jean Webster Papers are a section of material on Jean Webster' s boarding school, the Lady Jane Grey School, and the Adelaide Crapsey material. The Lady Jane Grey material consists mainly of copies of the Mosaic, the school's magazine or newsletter, as well as some miscellaneous information on the history of the school and Binghamton itself. The second supplement, the Adelaide Crapsey material, consists mainly of final drafts of most of Crapsey's poems. Also included is some biographical information and correspondence from Crapsey to Webster, and Crapsey's mother, Adelaide Trowbridge Crapsey, to Jean McKinney and Ethelyn McKinney. The researcher should note that although the originals of Crapsey's poems are restricted due to their fragility, all of them have been photocopied to ensure access.
Most dates in brackets were derived from the record of submissions and publications in folder 19.1
The Jean Webster Papers form part of the McKinney Family Papers.
Access
Originals of the Adelaide Crapsey poems are restricted; researchers must use the photocopies. The rest of the collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Related Materials
McKinney Family Papers
Samuel L. Clemens Papers
Subject Headings
Names:
Crapsey, Adelaide, 1878-1914; McKinney, Glenn Ford, 1869-1934; McKinney, Ethelyn, 1871-1964; Webster, Annie Moffett; Lewis, Emily Westwood; McKinney family
Organizations:
Lady Jane Grey School
Subjects:
Authors; Women authors--Fiction
Places:
Europe--Description and travel; Ireland--Description and travel; Asia--Description and travel; Africa--Description and travel
Document Types:
Scrapbooks; Journals (accounts); Photographs
VCL Categories
Children and Children's Literature; Family; Literature and Writing; Travel
Note
Forms part of the McKinney Family Papers.
Encoding Information
Encoded by Elizabeth Clarke, July 2007.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Jean McKinney Connor, daughter of Jean Webster and Glenn Ford McKinney, and her husband Ralph Connor, a former trustee of Vassar.
Series List
- Series I. Correspondence, (Boxes 1-2)
- Series II. Writings, (Boxes 3-17)
- Series III. Notes and Notebooks, (Boxes 17-24)
- Series IV. Clippings, Press Notices, Playbills, (Boxes 25-26)
- Series V. Scrapbooks, (Boxes 27-32)
- Series VI. Business, (Boxes 33-34)
- Series VII. Personal Business, (Box 34)
- Series VIII. Estate of Jean Webster, (Box 35)
- Series IX. Seances, (Box 35)
- Series X. Photographs, (Boxes 35-39, 48, 49, 50)
- Series XI. Memorabilia, (Boxes 39-41, 51)
- Series XII. Lady Jane Grey School Material, (Box 42)
- Series XIII. Adelaide Crapsey Material, (Boxes 43-47)
Container List
- Series I. Correspondence
  - Letters from Jean Webster
    - Lewis, Emily Westwood, 1915-1916; (7 items) (Folder 1.1)
    - McKinney, Ethelyn, 1908-1909; (4 items) (Folder 1.2)
    - McKinney, Ethelyn, 1910-1914; (2 items) (Folder 1.3)
    - Platt, Louise B., 1906; (1 item) (Folder 1.4)
    - Sickley, Katherine, 1903-1905; (5 items) (Folder 1.5)
    - Sickley, Katherine, 1906-1915; (3 items) (Folder 1.6)
    - Webster, Annie Moffett, 1900; (1 item) (Folder 1.7)
    - Webster, Annie Moffett, Jan-Feb 1907; (6 items) (Folder 1.8)
    - Webster, Annie Moffett, Mar-Apr 1907; (8 items) (Folder 1.9)
    - Webster, Annie Moffett, May-June 1907; (16 items) (Folder 1.10)
    - Webster, Sam, May 1907; (1 item) (Folder 1.11)
    - Weinstein, Lena, 1907-1914; (4 items) (Folder 1.12)
    - Unidentified Persons, 1908; (2 items) (Folder 1.13)
  - Letters to Jean Webster
    - Chatterton, Ruth, 1916; (1 item) (Folder 2.1)
    - Chiusarelli, G. Grifoni, 1905; (1 item) (Folder 2.2)
    - Doty, Douglas, 1912; (1 item) (Folder 2.3)
    - Eakin, Judy, n.d.; (1 item) (Folder 2.4)
    - Flexner, Anne Crawford, 1915; (1 item) (Folder 2.5)
    - Girardol, Etienne, 1914; (1 item) (Folder 2.6)
    - Hall, Fred J., 1915; (1 item) (Folder 2.7)
    - Harvey, George, 1905, n.d.; (2 items) (Folder 2.8)
    - Myers, J.B., 1917; (1 item) (Folder 2.9)
    - Nobata, Hero, 1911-1912, n.d.; (3 items) (Folder 2.10)
    - Phillips, Harriet S., 1915; (1 item) (Folder 2.11)
    - Ricklar, Norval, 1919; (1 item) (Folder 2.12)
    - Travina, Marie, 1916; (1 item) (Folder 2.13)
    - Watrous, Truman O., 1916; (1 item) (Folder 2.14)
    - Weinstein, Lena M., 1911; (6 items) (Folder 2.15)
  - Correspondence to Jean Webster McKinney's Family
    - Letters to Ralph and Jean McKinney Connor
      - Gordon, Peter, 1977; (1 item) (Folder 2.16)
      - Lady Jane Grey School, 1927; (1 item) (Folder 2.17)
      - Norcross, Emily Lewis, 1975-1982; (3 items) (Folder 2.18)
    - Letters from Sally Connor
      - "Rona", fan of Jean Webster, 1956; (1 item) (Folder 2.19)
    - Ethelyn and Glenn Ford McKinney: Cards and letters of condolence
      - announcement of Jean Webster's death, 11 June 1916 (Folder 2.20)
      - notecard by Glenn Ford McKinney, 11 June 1916 (Folder 2.20)
      - Unknown, June 1916; (1 item) (Folder 2.20)
      - Unknown, June 1916; (1 item) (Folder 2.20)
      - Allen, Renée Kelley, Aug 1916; (1 item) (Folder 2.20)
      - Ally, June 1916; (1 item) (Folder 2.20)
      - Andrews, Isabel, June 1916; (1 item) (Folder 2.20)
      - Asands, Mary, June 1916; (1 item) (Folder 2.20)
      - Cannon, Beulah, June 1916; (1 item) (Folder 2.20)
      - Clark, Mrs. John Bates, June 1916; (1 item) (Folder 2.20)
      - Coman, C.B., June 1916; (1 item) (Folder 2.20)
      - Cummings, Mabel, June 1916; (1 item) (Folder 2.20)
      - Dalrymple, Lila, June 1916; (1 item) (Folder 2.21)
      - Dorsey, Mr/Mrs Grafton D., June 1916; (2 items) (Folder 2.21)
      - Doty, Douglas Z., 1916; (2 items) (Folder 2.21)
      - Eakin, June 1916; (1 item) (Folder 2.21)
      - Fennessy, Mr/Mrs, June 1916; (2 items) (Folder 2.21)
      - Flexner, Anne Crawford, June 1916; (1 item) (Folder 2.21)
      - Gallowhur, Mrs. William, June 1916; (1 item) (Folder 2.21)
      - Gertrude, June 1916; (2 items) (Folder 2.21)
      - Green, Mrs. Nathan, June 1916; (1 item) (Folder 2.21)
      - Hamlin, Mr/Mrs Herbert, June 1916; (2 items) (Folder 2.22)
      - Jarrett, Cora Hardy, June 1916; (1 item) (Folder 2.22)
      - Jelliffe, Dr. Smith Ely, June 1916; (1 item) (Folder 2.22)
      - LaMont, H.D., June 1916; (1 item) (Folder 2.22)
      - Lamudona, Estelle Morris, June 1916; (1 item) (Folder 2.22)
      - Lewis, Emily Westwood, June 1916; (1 item) (Folder 2.22)
      - Mendenhall, Dorothy Reed, June 1916; (1 item) (Folder 2.22)
      - Naumburg, Mr/Mrs Edward, June 1916; (1 item) (Folder 2.22)
      - Panet, Mme. A. Edouard, June 1916; (1 item) (Folder 2.22)
      - Platt, Alethea Hill, June 1916; (1 item) (Folder 2.22)
      - Scott, Carolyn P., June 1916; (1 item) (Folder 2.22)
      - Skinner, Maud, 1917; (1 item) (Folder 2.23)
      - Tachan, Flora, June 1916; (1 item) (Folder 2.23)
      - Tarsin, Algernon, June 1916; (1 item) (Folder 2.23)
      - Twachtman, Mrs. John, June 1916; (1 item) (Folder 2.23)
      - Webster, Will, June 1916; (1 item) (Folder 2.23)
      - Weinstein, Elizabeth, June 1916; (1 item) (Folder 2.23)
      - Wells, Florence, June 1916; (1 item) (Folder 2.23)
      - Wilson, Anne, 1917; (2 items) (Folder 2.23)
      - Woolley, Isabelle, June 1916; (1 item) (Folder 2.23)
      - tribute to Jean Webster, Jan 1917; (2 items) (Folder 2.23)
- Series II. Writings
  - "By Way of Revenge,", 1896; (MS, 25 p., 1 draft) (Folder 3.1)
  - His Rival, The "Psi U." Pin, 1896; (MS, 24 p., 1 draft) (Folder 3.2)
  - "From Peekskill to Tarrytown,", 1896; (TS, 10 p., 1 draft) (Folder 3.3)
  - "A Camera and a Baby," Vassar Miscellany, Jan 1898; (2 p.) (Folder 3.4)
  - "A Fatalistic Courtship," Vassar Miscellany, June 1899; (4 p.) (Folder 3.5)
  - "Haunted Tarn,", Summer 1899; (MS, 22 p., 2nd draft) (Folder 3.6)
  - "Haunted Tarn," Vassar Miscellany, Oct 1899; (4 p.) (Folder 3.7)
  - "The Heroism O' Larry Muldoon,", 1899; (MS, p. 1-20) (Folder 3.8)
  - "The Heroism O' Larry Muldoon,", 1899; (MS, p. 20-35) (Folder 3.9)
  - "The Heroism O' Larry Muldoon,", 1899; (MS, p. 9-48) (Folder 3.10)
  - "The Heroism O' Larry Muldoon," Vassar Miscellany, Jan 1900; (7 p.) (Folder 3.11)
  - Vassar Notes, Poughkeepsie Sunday Courier, 1900 (Folder 3.12)
  - Vassar Notes: see also Vassariana 378.7V EW39
  - Italian Notes: description, language, etc., ca.1898-1900; (MS, 28 p.) (Folder 3.13)
  - Italian Notes: history, ca. 1898-1900; (MS, 26 p.) (Folder 3.14)
  - Italian Notes: articles, etc., ca. 1898-1900; (MS, 68 p.) (Folder 3.15)
  - Italian Notes: literature, etc., ca. 1898-1900; (MS, 6 p.) (Folder 3.16)
  - "Pauperism in Italy,", 1900; (MS, 33 p., 1 draft) (Folder 3.17)
  - "La Vie Parisienne,", ca. 1900; (TS, 38 p.) (Folder 4.1)
  - "Villa Gianini" (earliest version of The Wheat Princess), Vassar Miscellany, Apr 1901; (7 p.) (Folder 4.2)
  - "The Socialism of William Morris," Vassar College Senior Paper, 1901; (TS, 39 p.) (Folder 4.3)
  - "The Rejuvenated Mr. Moser,", [Feb 1902]; (TS, 23 p., 1 draft) (Folder 4.4)
  - "A Gentlemanly Burglar,", [Feb 1902]; (TS w/notes, 45 p., 2 drafts) (Folder 4.5)
  - "West Room at Kelsing Manor,", [Feb 1902]; (TS, 34 p., 1 draft) (Folder 4.6)
  - "Ugolina of Biella,", [Aug 1907]; (TS w/notes, 26 p., 1 draft, fragment) (Folder 4.7)
  - "Enter Ugolina," Story of Jean's Italian maid written by Annie Moffett Webster, ca. 1907; (MS, 7p.) (Folder 4.8)
  - "At the Four Seasons," part 1, [Sep 1907]; (TS, 21 p., 1 draft) (Folder 4.9)
  - "At the Four Seasons," part 2, [Sep 1907]; (TS, 22 p., 1 draft) (Folder 4.10)
  - "Citizens of the World," notes for a collection of foreign stories, 1907-1908; (MS, 5 p.) (Folder 4.11)
  - "Citizens of the World: From Rangoon to Mandalay," New Idea, 1907; (MS, 41 p., 1 draft) (Folder 4.12)
  - "Citizens of the World: At the Prome Pagoda," part 1, 1907; (MS notes, 4 p. TS w/notes, 49 p.) (Folder 4.13)
  - "Citizens of the World: At the Prome Pagoda," part 2, 1907; (TS w/notes, 39 p. 2 drafts) (Folder 4.14)
  - "Citizens of the World: On Lone Tree Hill," Smart Set, 1908 or 1909; (Ts w/notes, 24 p. 1 draft) (Folder 4.15)
  - "Citizens of the World: The Stolen Buddha,", n.d.; (MS, 31 p., 1 draft) (Folder 4.16)
  - Jerry Junior: dramatization of the novel, ca. 1907-1908; (MS notes, 39 index cards) (Folder 4.17)
  - Jerry Junior: dramatization of the novel, ca. 1907-1908; (MS, 32 p., fragment) (Folder 4.18)
  - Wheat Princess, Act I, [May-June 1908]; (TS, 45 p., copy 1) (Folder 5.1)
  - Wheat Princess, Act I, [May-June 1908]; (TS, 40 p., copy 2) (Folder 5.2)
  - Wheat Princess, Act II, [May-June 1908]; (TS, 33 p., copy 1) (Folder 5.3)
  - Wheat Princess, Act II, [May-June 1908]; (TS, 31 p., copy 2) (Folder 5.4)
  - Wheat Princess, Act III, [May-June 1908]; (TS, 29 p., copy 1) (Folder 5.5)
  - Wheat Princess, Act III, [May-June 1908]; (TS, 28 p., copy 2) (Folder 5.6)
  - Wheat Princess, Act IV, [May-June 1908]; (TS, 34 p., copy 1) (Folder 5.7)
  - Wheat Princess, Act IV, [May-June 1908]; (TS, 34 p., copy 2) (Folder 5.8)
  - Terry Patten (The Four Pools Mystery) material, ca. 1908; (MS/TS, 31 p., notes and fragments) (Folder 5.9)
  - Terry Patten, short detective stories, ca. 1908; (notebook, MS, 32 p. notes, fragments) (Folder 5.10)
  - Terry Patten: Poetic Justice, 1908; (TS, 30 p., 1 draft, notes) (Folder 5.11)
  - "Terry Patten: A Case of Poetic Justice,", Nov 1908; (TS w/notes, 30 p., 1 draft, fragments signed by JW) (Folder 5.12)
  - When Dreams Come True: "The Primrose Way,", Jan-Mar 1909; (TS, 48 p., 1 draft) (Folder 5.13)
  - When Dreams Come True, Act I, 1909; (TS, 43 p., copy 1) (Folder 5.14)
  - When Dreams Come True, Act I, 1909; (TS, 43 p., copy 2) (Folder 5.15)
  - When Dreams Come True, Act I, 1909; (TS, 43 p., copy 3) (Folder 5.16)
  - When Dreams Come True, Act I, 1909; (TS, 41 p., copy 4) (Folder 5.17)
  - When Dreams Come True, Act II, 1909; (TS, 54 p., copy 1) (Folder 6.1)
  - When Dreams Come True, Act II, 1909; (TS, 54 p., copy 2) (Folder 6.2)
  - When Dreams Come True, Act II, 1909; (TS, 49 p., copy 3) (Folder 6.3)
  - When Dreams Come True, Act II, 1909; (TS, 50 p., copy 4) (Folder 6.4)
  - When Dreams Come True, Act III, 1909; (TS, 33 p., copy 1) (Folder 6.5)
  - When Dreams Come True, Act III, 1909; (TS, 33 p., copy 2) (Folder 6.6)
  - When Dreams Come True, Act III, 1909; (TS, 32 p., copy 3) (Folder 6.7)
  - When Dreams Come True, Act III, 1909; (TS, 32 p., copy 4) (Folder 6.8)
  - When Dreams Come True, Act IV, 1909; (TS, 33 p., copy 1) (Folder 6.9)
  - When Dreams Come True, Act IV, 1909; (TS, 27 p., copy 2) (Folder 6.10)
  - When Dreams Come True, Act IV, 1909; (TS, 34 p., copy 3) (Folder 6.11)
  - When Dreams Come True, Act IV, 1909; (TS, 33 p., copy 4) (Folder 7.1)
  - When Dreams Come True, Act I, Aug 1910; (TS, 41 p., carbon copy 4th form) (Folder 7.2)
  - When Dreams Come True, Act II, Aug 1910; (TS, 53 p., carbon copy 4th form) (Folder 7.3)
  - When Dreams Come True, Act III, Aug 1910; (TS, 31 p., carbon copy 4th form) (Folder 7.4)
  - When Dreams Come True, Act IV, Aug 1910; (TS, 30 p., carbon copy 4th form) (Folder 7.5)
  - When Dreams Come True, Act I, 1910; (TS, 43 p., carbon copy final revision) (Folder 7.6)
  - When Dreams Come True, Act II, 1910; (TS, 53 p., carbon copy) (Folder 7.7)
  - When Dreams Come True, Act III, 1910; (TS, 31 p., carbon copy) (Folder 7.8)
  - When Dreams Come True, Act IV, 1910; (TS, 30 p., carbon copy) (Folder 7.9)
  - When Dreams Come True, Act I, used at Empire Theater, Nov 4, 1909; (TS, 42 p., prompt copy) (Folder 7.10)
  - When Dreams Come True, Act II, ibid.; (TS, 50 p., prompt copy) (Folder 7.11)
  - When Dreams Come True, Act III, used at Empire Theater, Nov 4, 1909; (TS, 33 p., prompt copy) (Folder 8.1)
  - When Dreams Come True, Act IV, ibid.; (TS, 35 p., prompt copy) (Folder 8.2)
  - When Dreams Come True, Act II, (TS, 52 p., incomplete copy) (Folder 8.3)
  - When Dreams Come True, Act III, (TS, 54 p., incomplete copy) (Folder 8.4)
  - Parable for Wives: scenario of a 3-act play, ca. Oct 1909; (TS, 14 p.) (Folder 8.5)
  - Parable for Wives: scenario of a 3-act play, ca. Oct 1909; (TS/MS, 18 p.) (Folder 8.6)
  - "Parable for Wives," short story, [Feb 1910]; (TS, 27 p. 1 draft) (Folder 8.7)
  - "Parable for Wives,", [Feb 1910]; (copy 2, TS, 20 p.) (Folder 8.8)
  - "Parable for Wives,", [Feb 1910]; (copy 3, TS, 20 p.) (Folder 8.9)
  - "Cape Cod Stories," notes, ca. Feb 1910; (MS, 24 p., fragments) (Folder 8.10)
  - "Cape Cod Stories: At the Golden Gate,", Feb 6, 1910; (TS w/notes, 22 p. 1 draft) (Folder 8.11)
  - "Cape Cod Stories: At the Golden Gate,", ca. Feb 1910; (TS, 24 p., 1 draft, notes, copy 2) (Folder 8.12)
  - "Cape Cod Stories: Roller Skating vs. Mining Stock,", Feb 16, 1910; (TS, 11 p., fragment ) (Folder 9.1)
  - "Cape Cod Stories: How Nausett Got the Band,", ca. Feb 1910; (TS w/notes, 17 p 1 draft) (Folder 9.2)
  - "Cape Cod Stories: Ezry's Dilemma,", ca. Feb 1910; (TS, 6 p., fragment) (Folder 9.3)
  - The Pigs of Palestrina — miscellaneous material, n.d.; (TS, 18 p.) (Folder 9.4)
  - The Pigs of Palestrina, 1912; (TS, 41 p., p. 1-39) (Folder 9.5)
  - The Pigs of Palestrina, 1912; (TS, 43 p., p. 41-83) (Folder 9.6)
  - The Pigs of Palestrina, 1912; (TS, 27 p., p. 85-111) (Folder 9.7)
  - The Pigs of Palestrina, 1912; (TS, 35 p., p. 113-146) (Folder 9.8)
  - The Pigs of Palestrina, 1912; (TS, 30 p., p. 148-175) (Folder 9.9)
  - The Pigs of Palestrina, Introduction and Part I, 1912; (TS, 41 p.) (Folder 9.10)
  - The Pigs of Palestrina, Part II, 1912; (TS, 44 p.) (Folder 9.11)
  - The Pigs of Palestrina, Part III, 1912; (TS, 28 p.) (Folder 9.12)
  - The Pigs of Palestrina, Part IV, 1912; (TS, 35 p.) (Folder 10.1)
  - The Pigs of Palestrina, Part V, 1912; (TS, 29 p.) (Folder 10.2)
  - The Pigs of Palestrina: see also Jean Webster's notebooks 19.1, 19.5, 19.6, and 19.7
  - Ceylon Tea Plantation, misc. notes, ca. 1912; (MS, 55 p.) (Folder 10.3)
  - Ceylon Tea Plantation, misc. notes, notebook, ca. 1912; (14 p.) (Folder 10.4)
  - Ceylon Tea Plantation, Scene 1, ca. 1912; (MS, 13 p.) (Folder 10.5)
  - Ceylon Tea Plantation, Scene 2, ca. 1912; (MS, 10 p.) (Folder 10.6)
  - Ceylon Tea Plantation, Scene 3, ca. 1912; (MS, 38 p.) (Folder 10.7)
  - Ceylon Tea Plantation, Scene 4, ca. 1912; (MS, 53 p.) (Folder 10.8)
  - Ceylon Tea Plantation, Scene 5, ca. 1912; (MS, 3 p.) (Folder 10.9)
  - Ceylon Tea Plantation, Scene 6, ca. 1912; (MS, 17 p.) (Folder 10.10)
  - Ceylon Tea Plantation, Scene 7, ca. 1912; (MS, 16 p.) (Folder 10.11)
  - Ceylon Tea Plantation, Scene 8, ca. 1912; (MS, 11 p.) (Folder 11.1)
  - Ceylon Tea Plantation, Scene 1, ca. 1912; (TS, 5 p.) (Folder 11.2)
  - Ceylon Tea Plantation, Scene 2, ca. 1912; (TS, 4 p.) (Folder 11.3)
  - Ceylon Tea Plantation, Scene 3, ca. 1912; (TS, 10 p.) (Folder 11.4)
  - Ceylon Tea Plantation, Scene 4, ca. 1912; (TS, 17 p.) (Folder 11.5)
  - Ceylon Tea Plantation, Scene 5, ca. 1912; (TS, 2 p.) (Folder 11.6)
  - Ceylon Tea Plantation, Southern Cross version — notes, ca. 1912; (MS, 11 p.) (Folder 11.7)
  - Ceylon Tea Plantation, Southern Cross version — scenario, ca. 1912; (TS, 21 p.) (Folder 11.8)
  - Ceylon Tea Plantation, The Equator — psychological scenario, ca. 1912; (MS, 41 p.) (Folder 11.9)
  - Ceylon Tea Plantation, The Equator — scenario, Acts I and II, ca. 1912; (MS, 35 p.) (Folder 11.10)
  - Ceylon Tea Plantation, The Equator — scenario, Act III, ca. 1912; (MS, 37 p.) (Folder 11.11)
  - Ceylon Tea Plantation, Step-Aside version — scenario and notes, ca. 1912; (TS, 38 p.) (Folder 11.12)
  - Ceylon Tea Plantation, Step Aside — reading notes, plot outline, 1912; (MS, 50 p.) (Folder 11.13)
  - Ceylon Tea Plantation: see also "On Lone Tree Hill", Folder 4.14
  - "Half a Loaf," notes, plot outline, Dec 1912; (2 notebooks, 146 p.) (Folder 11.14)
  - "Half a Loaf,", Dec 1912; (1 notebook, 4 p.) (Folder 12.1)
  - "Half a Loaf," notes, Dec 1912; (MS, 76 p.) (Folder 12.2)
  - "Half a Loaf,", Dec 1912; (corrected TS, 9 p.) (Folder 12.3)
  - "Half a Loaf,", Dec 1912; (MS, 9 p., fragment) (Folder 12.4)
  - "Half a Loaf": see also notebook 22.1
  - Daddy Long-Legs, material describing scenes and characters, ca. 1913; (TS, 34 p.) (Folder 12.5)
  - Daddy Long-Legs, scenario, 1913; (TS w/notes, 71 p.) (Folder 12.6)
  - Daddy Long-Legs, 1913; (corrected TS, 14 p.) (Folder 12.7)
  - Daddy Long-Legs, "old version," Act I, 1913; (TS/MS, 28 p.) (Folder 12.8)